<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- RSS generated by opmltweets v1.4.10 on Sun, 12 Jun 2022 16:14:14 GMT -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:source="http://source.scripting.com/">
	<channel>
		<title>mathling tweets</title>
		<link>http://twitter.com/mathling</link>
		<description>A feed of recent tweets from mathling.</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 13:58:52 GMT</pubDate>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<generator>opmltweets v1.4.10</generator>
		<docs>http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 16:14:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<cloud domain="rpc.rsscloud.io" port="5337" path="/pleaseNotify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
		<source:account service="twitter">mathling</source:account>
		<source:localTime>Sun, June 12, 2022 12:14 PM EDT</source:localTime>
		<item>
			<description>A long but informative thread, and waaay down thread another long thread in response&#10;At some level a deeply inside-the-beltway scientific spat&#10;At another level a seething political fight of great import&#10;And a view of what &quot;self-correcting&quot; science means in the trenches https://t.co/fL47tHZExI&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 13:58:52 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/mathling/status/1534535432934830082</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/mathling/status/1534535432934830082</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">mathling</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>GenerativeArt interlude</title>
			<description>Sunset on Paros&#10;#XQuery #SVG https://t.co/Tu8lwwCkmq&#10;&#10;A larger sun https://t.co/t0hej81f5j&#10;&#10;Last one: a rockier island. https://t.co/SrxEBnFhYW&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 18:08:58 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/mathling/status/1533873597290139648</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/mathling/status/1533873597290139648</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">mathling</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>All these incredibly bad takes about Ohio's anti-trans anti-girl anti-sports law, buying into the idea that &quot;fairness&quot; demands something like it.&#10;Pfeh. Fairness, where to even start?&#10;Look, I've played youth sport. I've coached youth sport.  Boys and girls, hundreds of 'em&#10;&#10;You know what ALL those kids have in common? Every last blessed one of them?&#10;&#10;They just want to hang out with their friends and play&#10;&#10;They want to have a feeling of joy in camaraderie and movement&#10;&#10;That's it.&#10;&#10;So let them.&#10;&#10;Were there huge variations in physical ability and skill&#10;Yes, huge&#10;&#10;Some of those kids had extra training, off-season teams. Fair? Not really.&#10;&#10;We had asthmatics trying to run for an hour on grass&#10;Fair? Not really.&#10;&#10;We had kids trying to stick with Ramadan fasting restrictions and play tournaments. Fair? Not really.&#10;&#10;This being soccer the best players had the &quot;unfair&quot; advantage of growing up where everyone played and watched their whole lives vs those who first kicked a ball last week&#10;&#10;Some of *those* girls, man, they could have run circles round most of the boys&#10;&#10;And frankly, as they teach you in ref school, the girls are way more aggressive w/ each other, so stick your stereotypes about poor fragile girls in the bin where it belongs&#10;&#10;Of all the hundreds of kids I coached, maybe two had the skill and athleticism to maybe make a top-tier high-school level club team. Maybe.&#10;&#10;Sure, sports parents are crazy, but folks, none of your darlings is getting the free-ride to Stanford, much less a pro contract.&#10;&#10;Chillax.&#10;&#10;Let the kids play&#10;&#10;You don't need to have some creep probe your daughter's innards to protect the sacred integrity of youth sports&#10;&#10;There is no sacred integrity&#10;&#10;The kids just want to hang with their friends and have fun&#10;&#10;So let them&#10;&#10;Thus endeth the rant&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 14:51:06 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/mathling/status/1533823801506418690</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/mathling/status/1533823801506418690</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">mathling</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<title>GenerativeArt interlude</title>
			<description>A study in symmetry&#10;#XQuery #SVG https://t.co/dQrunQ5ViN&#10;&#10;The basic skeleton is formed with a random sequence of horizontal and vertical lines, which is then mutated with a random series of horizontal and vertical flips, inversions, and reversals. Flip those two paths through horizontal and vertical to get the symmetry https://t.co/5Y9Y2kg3Bi&#10;&#10;There's a lot of variation in the design from this simple algorithm https://t.co/iw6nB7GWqk&#10;&#10;Solid colouring with contrasting lines https://t.co/L2GrVCgnms&#10;&#10;Gradient colouring, showing some of the variability https://t.co/odmEYI01HZ&#10;&#10;Solid colouring gives a different vibe https://t.co/hgzq4MOQJU&#10;&#10;Incomplete symmetry: when we only include the horizontally flipped and vertically flipped variants, but not the variant that flips both https://t.co/4rwb0g8m3u&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 18:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/mathling/status/1533152353880133632</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/mathling/status/1533152353880133632</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">mathling</source:account>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
