<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- RSS generated by opmltweets v1.4.10 on Tue, 31 May 2022 14:50:48 GMT -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:source="http://source.scripting.com/">
	<channel>
		<title>_am1t tweets</title>
		<link>http://twitter.com/_am1t</link>
		<description>A feed of recent tweets from _am1t.</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 14:50:25 GMT</pubDate>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<generator>opmltweets v1.4.10</generator>
		<docs>http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 14:50:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<cloud domain="rpc.rsscloud.io" port="5337" path="/pleaseNotify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
		<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
		<source:localTime>Tue, May 31, 2022 10:50 AM EDT</source:localTime>
		<item>
			<description>I love what Grammarly can do – but boy, its Premium tier is costly. Ironically, every time it corrects me, I want to pay for the service. But then I see how much it costs &amp;amp; I can’t convince myself that I need it enough. I tried LanguageTool for a year, but reconsidering now.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 14:50:25 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531649303994941440</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531649303994941440</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I am tired of even the simple utility apps going for subscription model instead of right out one-time purchases. Make the app a paid app – sure make it costlier than the subscription cost. Don’t say it’s free and present “Subscribe” button first thing ... https://t.co/ZUTyBrS0eU&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 11:58:49 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531606120942411776</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531606120942411776</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>When writing, and also when doing research for writing, it’s important to get the details right, but that doesn’t always mean what you might think. Economy of detail is usually better than excess, which raises the critical question about which details ... https://t.co/Do3cUcmtkt&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 10:59:28 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531591184933605377</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531591184933605377</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Every now and then, there’s an XKCD comic which I can make no sense of. Today’s (or XKCD 2626) was such. I am not that smart you see 😄 https://t.co/ZY7zU163oR&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 10:04:45 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531577414177923074</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531577414177923074</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@mattgemmell Interesting. And I agree, it should be optimised in the other direction — longer, but less wider is better I guess.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 09:49:54 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531573678823309312</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531573678823309312</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>To be lonely, then, is to desire an absent want. It is to feel an emptiness that remains unsatisfied — to feel isolated, in need, or abandoned, but with no one to help. Yet solitude is another thing altogether. To be solitary is to retreat into ... https://t.co/4VeNpZF6s0&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 06:43:46 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531526836211134464</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531526836211134464</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I have replaced Windows on my laptop today with Linux – basically, I installed the Lubuntu distro. But that was only because I had a bootable drive ready with Lubuntu. As I then checked for the updates on the distro, I realized so much has changed ... https://t.co/5Q44jWdbot&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 09:03:26 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531199593601458176</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1531199593601458176</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>“Staying up late does not give you more time. It delays the renumeration against the work your body has put in throughout the day. It might be pleasing in the moment, but it also begins a countdown towards ruining a day in the coming week for ... https://t.co/7ni6ttUS3X&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 16:55:12 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530593545320636416</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530593545320636416</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I am looking forward to today’s qualifier between RR and RCB. I have always loved the play RR plays – always the underdogs on paper, but punch above their weight. This time they are strong on paper too. I am hoping for a  the first qualifier rematch in the IPL finals.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 14:01:23 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530187413506629634</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530187413506629634</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>It’s best to put emoji at the very end of your written content which also means not using them as bullet points. This practice will help you avoid creating any clarity issues that could be caused by an icon’s coded description interfering with the ... https://t.co/YKVizoxXVv&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 12:00:06 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530156892101783552</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530156892101783552</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I let my subscription to the Freedom service expire today. I intend to do the same for Pocket soon. I don’t get enough benefit from either of these services. Plus I am at the peak of subscription fatigue now. Am done with annual subscriptions, doesn’t matter how cheap they are.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 10:59:05 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530141537337847808</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530141537337847808</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Every time I listen to the song Daryaa from Manmarziyaan, I am reminded of the genius of Amit Trivedi. It’s such an intricate, yet equally simple song. The whole album is a masterclass. Also Lootera, Bombay Velvet, Andhadhun – man, I am a big fan of ... https://t.co/CMhy5iXrzt&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 06:36:23 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530075425443028995</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530075425443028995</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>In line with one of my recent posts about writing for audience, this is a wonderful quote from Leo Tolstoy (h/t James Clear).&#10;If you care too much about being praised, in the end you will not accomplish anything serious. Let the judgments of others ... https://t.co/96GKOPeK7k&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 06:19:28 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530071167545008128</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1530071167545008128</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I use Firefox on Windows/iOS/Android and Safari on Mac. But the comparison that Brave publishes is effective. Browsers are sticky, there’s rarely an incentive to switch.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 17:08:41 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529872159270703105</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529872159270703105</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>A smartphone with a case is just not the same device. I have never used a device without a case ever. A slippery slab of fragile glass just doesn’t feel comfortable sitting in my hand. So, I just wrap it in a case and carry it along. It gives the ... https://t.co/qnpZC38BdL&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 12:01:15 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529794791713677317</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529794791713677317</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I like how the playoffs have lined up in this year’s IPL. The teams that played the best are the ones at the top. None is there that shouldn’t be. I would love a new champion this time, that means I support only one team of the remaining three — the Gujarat Titans.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 10:43:43 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529775281489289217</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529775281489289217</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Finished reading: Dark Matter: A Novel by Blake Crouch 📚&#10;It had a brilliant premise — unique and fascinating. However, I didn’t enjoy the many turns it took in the second half. There were a lot of moments when the book felt stretched, unnecessarily ... https://t.co/oJOP5pKLqC&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 07:13:21 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529722341860728834</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529722341860728834</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Suppose China ends up invading and successfully annexing Taiwan; what would happen to the 2.7 million registered domains under .tw?&#10;Source: What happens to TLDs when their country stops existing? →&#10;Another reason I tend to prefer a few specific TLDs. https://t.co/QWX7zaIYDO&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 12:21:41 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529437547616735232</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529437547616735232</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Writing publicly, with the voice of your readers chirping at the back of your mind, is ineffective. You write for interaction – that’s futile. Most social media posts belong to this category that. You are reined back by the voice — you write for ... https://t.co/Aezjr25JcZ&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 14:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529100583507992577</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529100583507992577</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I recently finished watching The Lincoln Lawyer on Netflix. It’s a good, bingeworthy series. Nothing’s great about it, but if all one wants is to binge a show over the weekend, this is one option. The things keep moving. No performance is painful, no side-story unbearable.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 11:51:36 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529067587572846592</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529067587572846592</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>[D]esigning a language to be minimalistic, to have fewer concepts, and to choose primitives that combine well together, is a good way to make the language easier to learn. If the programming language has fewer concepts, there’s less to learn, and your ... https://t.co/v2SuWBQKdU&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 11:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529059229503561728</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1529059229503561728</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I recently got to know (h/t Gabriel) that “On This Day” feature doesn’t work with the Paper theme. I fixed the issue – the micro memories should load properly now. I have also fixed a few minor styling issues. The upgrade should be available in the ... https://t.co/LPhldzdLyX&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 12:02:26 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1528707925472120837</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1528707925472120837</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I want you to know that most of your life will happen in the gray spaces between bliss and heartbreak, between having everything lock into place and having it all fall apart. That’s where the grace is.&#10;Source: Laura Dern writes to her teenage daughter → https://t.co/hkCSCx5wJ0&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 10:52:24 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1528690301304549377</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1528690301304549377</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>I have been traveling for the past week – rejuvenating myself amidst the nature. Relaxing on the beach. Had some wonderful rides, surrounded by dense jungles. Most of all, untouched by all the hustle bustle of the modern life. Wonder. Amazement. Serenity. https://t.co/kptC82IVDj&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 04:27:04 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1528593328593424384</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1528593328593424384</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Who’s on first?→&#10;Abbott and Costello perform the classic “Who’s on first?” baseball sketch in their 1945 film “The Naughty Nineties” first performed as part of their stage act. https://t.co/sXxdOzh1br&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 15:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1524413020021141504</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/_am1t/status/1524413020021141504</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">_am1t</source:account>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
