<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- RSS generated by opmltweets v1.4.10 on Mon, 30 May 2022 01:26:10 GMT -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:source="http://source.scripting.com/">
	<channel>
		<title>yudel tweets</title>
		<link>http://twitter.com/yudel</link>
		<description>A feed of recent tweets from yudel.</description>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 01:17:46 GMT</pubDate>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<generator>opmltweets v1.4.10</generator>
		<docs>http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 01:26:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<cloud domain="rpc.rsscloud.io" port="5337" path="/pleaseNotify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
		<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
		<source:localTime>Sun, May 29, 2022 9:26 PM EDT</source:localTime>
		<item>
			<description>@cakesandcourage How many cars did they license in all? Did they ever have to spring for four digits?&#10;&#10;@cakesandcourage My grandfather told me the first car he remembered seeing was in the Atlanta WWI Victory Parade.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 01:17:46 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531082405867577344</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531082405867577344</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@trekonomics I don’t know with you. You complain that Vichy gave in too soon, and here these spammers are persistent and still you kvetch.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 01:14:34 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531081601169375232</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531081601169375232</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@ShulimLeifer @EvelKneidel @doctorscience @yaffedorg @Yakovolf @OJPAC @NYSEDNews @errollouis Here’s my report of some frum reactions to Obama’s election. https://t.co/Vrd8dG5kXR&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:36:10 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531071937765462016</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531071937765462016</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@BunnyAdvocate @dman4835 @AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety Separately: Everything about American constitutional jurisprudence is up for grabs. The Court had announced that precedents are no longer binding. That means everything.&#10;&#10;@BunnyAdvocate @dman4835 @AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety I expect this to be reflected in dramatically rising costs of libel insurance, certainly in Fifth Circuit states.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531063385919475712</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531063385919475712</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@dman4835 @BunnyAdvocate @AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety Filing a lawsuit does not necessarily cost a lot of money. (I have not yet googled Texas court fees.) And it might get some attention from Meta.&#10;&#10;@dman4835 @BunnyAdvocate @AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety I expect the Supremes to overturn on interstate commerce grounds.&#10;&#10;@dman4835 @BunnyAdvocate @AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety But they may delay to send a signal that they think the Fifth Court’s heart is in the right place.&#10;&#10;@dman4835 @BunnyAdvocate @AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety I also think that last week’s Ninth Court ruling mostly overturning Florida’s social media law does give room for demanding that IG preserve records of bans for more than 30 days.&#10;&#10;@dman4835 @BunnyAdvocate @AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety I think there is also a related libel claim since IG alleged I violated their policies.&#10;&#10;@dman4835 @BunnyAdvocate @AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety Which unless being a very lame poster violates their terms, I don’t believe I was.&#10;&#10;@dman4835 @BunnyAdvocate @AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety Only thing I can figure is that I posted an image like this of the most recent book I published. https://t.co/02QzDRUVXv&#10;&#10;@dman4835 @BunnyAdvocate @AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety More details on the book here. https://t.co/sKadgJbVxQ&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 23:51:31 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531060699018969088</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531060699018969088</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Some old time religion, American-style https://t.co/9I5YqKGF9x&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:34:24 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531041292318347264</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531041292318347264</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@AShihipar In unity is strength. Like a bundle of sticks is so much more powerful than any one stick.&#10;&#10;@AShihipar Does she think this will save her from Gitmo when the show trials begin?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:29:20 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531040020139847681</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531040020139847681</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@aayushkrm @hardmaru I suspect that by 2035 that a computer can both write a script from a prompt and then generate the photorealistic movie.&#10;&#10;@aayushkrm @hardmaru Whether it will be a good script is a different question.&#10;&#10;@aayushkrm @hardmaru And how cheap it all is to generate.&#10;&#10;@aayushkrm @hardmaru Will it be able to generate a situation comedy or action adventure movie based on my prompting my obscure interest?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:20:55 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531037899768070145</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531037899768070145</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@Mad_Science_Guy @ZachWeiner Even if the equations are the same, the value of the variables have not.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:00:59 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531032882285887489</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531032882285887489</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@shaynamalka @LahavHarkov Is aluminum a required ingredient, or will they work in a glass pan of that size?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:44:33 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531013649342554113</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531013649342554113</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@Tzipshmil @owillis The Hindenburg Democrats. Who are objectively better than the Vichy Democrats we’ll be “voting” for in 2028.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:25:04 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531008745064607744</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531008745064607744</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@onthemainline @abesilbe @rabbimargulies @MisfitTorah Certainly that’s normative psak regarding the Czar. Didn’t the Vatican only mattir democracy circa 1890?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:23:56 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531008458862084096</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531008458862084096</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@abesilbe @rabbimargulies @MisfitTorah Yes. Kahane was theologically wrong. (His sociological insights are more mixed.) What Kahane gave me at that point of time was an English-language theology that explained the actions of Gush Emunim.&#10;&#10;@abesilbe @rabbimargulies @MisfitTorah That was helpful in my personal political journey, because while I was not qualified then to discuss security issues raised by the settlers and their supporters, I was qualified to dismiss Kahane’s theology.&#10;&#10;@abesilbe @rabbimargulies @MisfitTorah And as to the critique of my invoking Kahane: it’s important to understand when debating what is being contested.&#10;&#10;@abesilbe @rabbimargulies @MisfitTorah And back in my day at YU, a speech by Kahane on campus was much less problematic for the rabbinic faculty than was a talk by Rabbi Saul Berman, who was on the faculty of the school’s Stern College for Women but was an advocate for what now is called Open Orthodoxy.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 19:52:53 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531000646815604736</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1531000646815604736</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@MisfitTorah Kahane has explained that such use of power is actually a kiddush Hashem. I think it’s in one of his 80s books. Worth reading to understand that this is a theological disagreement you’re having.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 17:49:04 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530969485875851266</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530969485875851266</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Would watch! https://t.co/CSskdFFVYd&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 17:35:41 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530966121502986242</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530966121502986242</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Everybody knows about Yeshiva Rabbeinu Yitzchak Elchanan (aka YU's RIETS seminary) but who remembers the Elhanan Spektor Lodge of B'nai B'rith? https://t.co/RJI1kWu9Zd&#10;&#10;The October 29, 1897 issue of the the San Francisco Jewish publication currently known as J: The Jewish News of Northern California reports as follows: https://t.co/0xeYN1MTui&#10;&#10;A new B'nai B'rith Lodge, composed of Russian-born young men, is to be soon organized under the name of Elhanan Spektor Lodge. The name is well chosen. Elhanan Spektor, now gone to his reward, was in all respects the finest type of the scholar and Zaddig these years have produced https://t.co/bbtLVy7jgC&#10;&#10;Tolerant, just, pious and gentle, his virtues déserve commemoration amongst those of his countrymen who desire his name to be perpetuated on this side of the globe.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 15:16:05 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530930988142010370</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530930988142010370</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@gabrielwinant But it assumes punishment of this who don’t serve is more probable than punishment of those who are lefhanded.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 06:13:09 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530794353509154816</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530794353509154816</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@gabrielwinant It’s an embodiment of a fascist Christian theology, that *assumes* an all-powerful being would harbor infinite resentment.&#10;&#10;@gabrielwinant Which turns greed (wanting to have been created sooner) and resentment (punishing those who had not helped him) into divine values.&#10;&#10;@gabrielwinant It’s Ayn Rand meets Fire and Brinstone. So prototypically American.&#10;&#10;@gabrielwinant The fact people take it seriously implies a profound lack of philosophical training among seemingly smart people.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 06:01:55 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530791526787317760</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530791526787317760</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@Penprince_ Proving again he’s twice the man of most of us.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 05:37:34 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530785400989663233</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530785400989663233</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@EladNehorai If it’s any comfort, @instagram cancelled my seldom used, very lame @BenYehudaPress account for reasons they won’t deign to tell me because 30 days have expired and we all know how hard document retention is.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 05:31:39 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530783908672987136</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530783908672987136</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety Meanwhile, here’s one they’re not suspending: https://t.co/7kWfznLhen&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 05:29:31 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530783373232422914</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530783373232422914</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety Stupid, unappealable cancellation is really not viable. Speaking as such a victim.&#10;&#10;@AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety Charge $25 for a review by a real person. That would pay for 15 minutes of a real person’s time to review the offending post in context.&#10;&#10;@AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety Or charge $50 and refund half if the appeal is granted.&#10;&#10;@AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety But meanwhile he should file a complaint in Texas court.&#10;&#10;@AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety I’m actually considering notifying IG’s legal department of my intent to file. What *is* the Texas filing fee?&#10;&#10;@AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety How much would a Waco attorney charge to file if I were to draft the papers?&#10;&#10;@AkivaMCohen @TwitterSafety Happy to sign an affidavit that to the best of my recollection all my posts expressed the viewpoint that everyone should buy my Jewish books.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 05:03:35 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530776848912859136</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530776848912859136</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@alanabbey Looks familiar. Lax? EWR? Do all airports *except* BG look the same?&#10;&#10;@alanabbey Given that they’re collecting via PayPal, and PayPal notoriously is difficult for Palestinians to access, one has to question their authenticity.&#10;&#10;@alanabbey However, scamming Red Army supporters doesn’t bother me much so 🤷‍♂️&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 04:55:55 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530774916257177606</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530774916257177606</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@tamar_marvin @DBashIdeas This was indeed a fun one.&#10;&#10;@tamar_marvin @DBashIdeas What would be involved in creating supplemental volumes? Essential Papers on the Talmud from the Clinton Administration and After? (That volume is copyright ‘94.)&#10;&#10;@tamar_marvin @DBashIdeas Anyone who knows one of the fields covered by that NYU series and would like to curate a volume, my dms are open!&#10;&#10;@tamar_marvin @DBashIdeas Though I should probably start by asking Rabbi Chernick, whose Sunday morning Talmud shiur I was privileged to attend for several years.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 04:43:09 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530771706415132674</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530771706415132674</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@dick_nixon Sir, I am sorry to say you were not loved by the eight year olds in my suburban private liberal Jewish school in advance of your re-election.&#10;&#10;@dick_nixon And that was without any of us knowing the, shall we say, unseemly conversation you had on my eighth birthday which was 6/23/72. Kind of scars a ten-year-old’s faith in authority to learn how a president, even one he despised, obstructed justice on his eighth birthday.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 04:18:26 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530765484798402560</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530765484798402560</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
