<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- RSS generated by opmltweets v1.4.10 on Fri, 06 May 2022 18:49:19 GMT -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:source="http://source.scripting.com/">
	<channel>
		<title>yudel tweets</title>
		<link>http://twitter.com/yudel</link>
		<description>A feed of recent tweets from yudel.</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:44:41 GMT</pubDate>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<generator>opmltweets v1.4.10</generator>
		<docs>http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:49:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<cloud domain="rpc.rsscloud.io" port="5337" path="/pleaseNotify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
		<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
		<source:localTime>Fri, May 6, 2022 2:49 PM EDT</source:localTime>
		<item>
			<description>@notrivia @DrZackaryBerger Maybe look into who Gottheimer’s fundrrd are, and who else they find.&#10;&#10;@notrivia @DrZackaryBerger I had the occasion to look into the campaign contributions of a billionaire being picketed by @truahrabbis for opposing a labor agreement approved by all the other companies in his industry. https://t.co/J2d7ZvDToy&#10;&#10;@notrivia @DrZackaryBerger @truahrabbis Lo and behold, he funds  the Republican Party — and Senator Sinema and Congressman Gottheimer.&#10;&#10;@notrivia @DrZackaryBerger @truahrabbis Given the congressman’s willingness to tell lies about progressives — and to shout “antisemitism!” when called on it — not sure there’s any reason to take his claims in good faith.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:44:41 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522648561346916354</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522648561346916354</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@dylyricus @fmc_dylan I’d like clues as to which holiday it was.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:40:54 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522647612389838852</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522647612389838852</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>This is related to the fact that Israeli ultra orthodox leaders are fighting phones not under their control as a threat to their community’s staying faithful. https://t.co/S2I5KbxKPz&#10;&#10;Or the statement by my Talmud teacher at Yeshiva University that an honest, objective study of Judaism at the university’s graduate school — undertaken with academic methods but by Orthodox professors — would lead to apostasy.&#10;&#10;Because religious fundamentalism can’t survive an honest inquiry. And at the same time, the kind of “scholarship” promoted in yeshivas works very well to close off independent thought.&#10;&#10;As it is written: “Girls go to college to get more knowledge. Boys go to kollel on Jupiter to get more stupider.”&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:31:36 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522645271175434241</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522645271175434241</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@greg_shill Damn. Not a good look for William Shatner. https://t.co/XMXRpJ3lUM&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:28:09 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522644401549455361</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522644401549455361</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@kampeas @StateDept I think we have the premise of our next Trek series.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:23:47 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522643304722087941</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522643304722087941</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@AkivaMCohen When Stare Decis is dead, all is permitted.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 18:21:35 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522642751199789056</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522642751199789056</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@datadivajf @ansonmount @ListeningToFilm I am so here for this remake of The Counterclock World!&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 17:52:02 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522635313658667009</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522635313658667009</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@dzkalman https://t.co/TkalSnfUwO&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:35:51 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522616142648516608</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522616142648516608</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@dzkalman I’d like to have the song about him suing under the ADA to make 770 accessible for those who are 17 feet tall.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:35:15 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522615989208334342</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522615989208334342</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@EladNehorai And this is why the Administration is so maddening. They want to pretend that everything is 1998 when we’re galloping to Christofascism. https://t.co/LlQWUyXgro&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:30:45 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522614858377748480</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522614858377748480</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@HareianiBlog @rabbijilljacobs @eJPhil Is there anything less elite than perjuring oneself before Congress to cover up the massacre of peasants, and then getting a cushy non-profit post opining in ethics?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:35:52 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522601047625281537</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522601047625281537</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@3illSweet Shouldn’t Where Mo Man Has Gone Before be on that list?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:29:37 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522599471279972352</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522599471279972352</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@EbWatchesTrek Given that this episode added more characters whose stories will resonate with Spock’s loss — as well as strong reminders that Michael’s story is deeply classified — I suspect the writers are going there.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:15:58 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522596036467900416</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522596036467900416</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Tl;dr&amp;gt; My book debunking a Christian extremist reading of the Torah is free on the Kindle store for the next couple of days. Read on for the back story, and maybe a few tidbits. https://t.co/EjHpOCIoPz&#10;&#10;Back in the days of George W. Bush, the Forward featured David Klinghoffer as a regular conservative columnist. (The Forward was liberal at the time.) As is the ways of newspapers, he was never fact checked.&#10;&#10;And is the ways of conservatives — he was an editor at the National Review — he was a political operative, not a theologian. Though he had written a book about his &quot;Journey to Jewish Orthodoxy.&quot; https://t.co/qypJTQRv10&#10;&#10;Every installment I was tempted to write a rebuttal to the editor — but never did.&#10;&#10;So when I learned that he was putting out a book in advance of the 2008 election entitled “How Would God Vote: Why the Bible Commands You to Be a Conservative,&quot; I knew it demanded rebutting. https://t.co/uVhzDvw0El&#10;&#10;So I put out a call for collaborators to rebut the book --- ideally, within 30 days after its release, since an election was coming up.&#10;https://t.co/83j34Z5LVz&#10;&#10;As it happened, only one person answered my call: Yori Yanover, my boss at the Jewish Communications Network (AKA https://t.co/thUparRLOP) at the dawn of the Web  and author of &quot;The Cabalist's Daughter: A Novel of Practical Messianic Redemption Paperback.&quot; https://t.co/t6ot6Q9xdl&#10;&#10;So we divided Klinghoffer's chapters and wrote our rebuttals as fast as we could. We didn't attack all of his arguments -- he supported reparations for African Americans, and gun control in a nod to contrarianism -- and time of course was a limiting factor. https://t.co/OcMuCTnAAy&#10;&#10;But we did go after his attacks on gay marriage, feminism, divorce, evolution, progressive taxation, and health care (not just government funded health care -- he suggested that all medical care is bad because it will decrease people's tendency to pray. Really!) https://t.co/U3Tz1dREc3&#10;&#10;And we went after his calls for capital punishment, the drug war, and the Iraq War. As we bloggers used to say back in those days, we gave him a good fisking -- and offered readers some laughs along the way. https://t.co/jPMIJqitUK&#10;&#10;Did the book have an impact? Well, it came out before the election, and Obama won the election. On the other hand, the book sold dozens rather than hundreds of copies. On the third hand, David Klinghoffer never opined on Jewish affairs again. So a win? https://t.co/4Lo7gnrRjk&#10;&#10;Meanwhile, if you want to read some pilpul justifying the progressive opinions on these issues, and pick up some deep background on the nature of the religious right that has installed the current #RogueSCOTUS -- well, it's free! What do you have to lose? https://t.co/EjHpOCIoPz&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:13:07 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522595320328241154</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522595320328241154</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@RottenInDenmark @swordsjew Look at Gottheimer’s funders before you write that he “believes” this will help hold the House.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:06:04 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522593548201250818</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522593548201250818</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@ryanlcooper @swordsjew Maybe look into funding JoshG — and ask why he’s being funded by people who generally fund the Republican Party?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:01:54 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522592498132135937</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522592498132135937</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@onthemainline Non-fundamentalist religion?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:58:19 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522591595023020032</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522591595023020032</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@TheDCSentinel So we can assume that showing such little ability to predict the future will hurt her career at the Atlantic? Or is her job not to be smart, but to tell comforting lies about Republicans?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:31:11 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522584767060971521</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522584767060971521</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@bully_thelsb @typolad Shame the bridge computer no longer has a printer, however.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522578195844935680</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522578195844935680</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Shoutout to @trekonomics in the new Star Trek series? https://t.co/bb9ziW62mH&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 07:34:11 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522479824345911296</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522479824345911296</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>If only Abbie Hoffman were alive to see this moment. https://t.co/oXWtcxHi9f&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 05:16:41 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522445222168432641</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522445222168432641</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@dauntlessdalton @EladNehorai Nah, only about half. Lots of Republican doctors who don’t believe in demons and do believe in medicine.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 03:34:56 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522419618530398210</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522419618530398210</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@EladNehorai What might be worthwhile is reminding other Republicans that these are crazy fundamentalists who believe in literal demons and faith healing.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 03:27:55 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522417851801473025</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522417851801473025</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>What's the equivalent for &quot;The worst person in the world has made a good point,&quot; except it's &quot;The worst person in the world has had a Nazi quote he was attacking attributed to him and turned into a meme with his picture on it at https://t.co/IjIigsMuTj&quot;?&#10;&#10;And no, there's no contact form on the site or other way to ask them to correct it. And I (or the victim) couldn't in good faith sign a copyright takedown, since the actual quote belongs to a 1937 Nazi filmmaker ... at least according to said worst person's article.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 02:20:03 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522400770917810181</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522400770917810181</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@babyboymonaghan Was he right?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 01:35:01 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522389437883334661</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1522389437883334661</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
