<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- RSS generated by opmltweets v1.4.10 on Thu, 07 Jul 2022 08:39:21 GMT -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:source="http://source.scripting.com/">
	<channel>
		<title>yudel tweets</title>
		<link>http://twitter.com/yudel</link>
		<description>A feed of recent tweets from yudel.</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 08:27:13 GMT</pubDate>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<generator>opmltweets v1.4.10</generator>
		<docs>http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 08:39:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<cloud domain="rpc.rsscloud.io" port="5337" path="/pleaseNotify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
		<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
		<source:localTime>Thu, July 7, 2022 4:39 AM EDT</source:localTime>
		<item>
			<description>If I remember correctly, Rabin’s first government fell in the wake of an education minister’s resignation. This led to the election of Menachem Begin.&#10;&#10;Who despite campaigning as a Remainer was responsible for — how do you say it — Sexit.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 08:27:13 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544961221841096704</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544961221841096704</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@acandidworld @schraubd I still haven’t heard a compelling explanation of why AIPAC decided this was the election cycle to start funding candidates.&#10;&#10;@acandidworld @schraubd Seems like the most polarizing US election in over a century might not be the year to start dropping bundles of money wrapped in an Israeli flag on political campaigns.&#10;&#10;@acandidworld @schraubd I mean, a cynic might think that a Republican-leaning group felt that Republicans could use a new and loud endorsement at a time like this.&#10;&#10;@acandidworld @schraubd A cynic might wonder whether the unknown folks at AIPAC who decided on this course are more loyal to the interests of the Republican Party or to the State of Israel.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 06:44:18 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544935321821155328</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544935321821155328</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@dzkalman There are very few lines of communication between “younger” generations and the “leadership” cadres. Half go to Murdoch to find out what’s going on in the world; half go to the Times.&#10;&#10;@dzkalman And there is a very strong interest — which has multiple causes — in not attributing any blame for rising antisemitism to mainstream Republican culture, including Fox and Trump.&#10;&#10;@dzkalman The community is deeply broken and the press is effectively muzzled.&#10;&#10;@dzkalman Who in the business can call up a billionaire such as Bernie Marcus and say, “Now that the Republican youth group you helped fund is posting racist, antisemitic Nazi memes, do you have any second thoughts?”&#10;&#10;@dzkalman The charitable view is that leaders realize there’s no actually stopping hate and so have given up, and after all we can all flee to Israel so why bother.&#10;&#10;@dzkalman That would explain why the ADL web site has plans with fancy acronyms but doesn’t actually link to the legislation it supports.&#10;&#10;@dzkalman That might also explain the apparent lack of interest in debriefing convicted antisemitic criminals.&#10;&#10;@dzkalman And that would also explain why my congressman can weaponize false charges of antisemitism against Jewish political opponents on his left.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 06:29:05 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544931490017865728</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544931490017865728</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@ehnyay @EladNehorai It can’t afford to use high caliber reporting, because like the NYTimes and the Atlantic, it wants to appear “nonpartisan.”&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 06:26:26 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544930825191403520</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544930825191403520</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@trekonomics One of the downsides of being ruled by people who came of age before the acceptance of plate tectonics.&#10;&#10;@trekonomics I mean, how seriously was geology treated at a Catholic high school circa 1960?&#10;&#10;@trekonomics At least students at the Talmudic Institute of Upstate New York had statewide standardized tests to aspire to, if one was so inclined. Did Delaware?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 06:18:42 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544928876278972416</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544928876278972416</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@YehudisFletcher @Anzovina @cwjisrael @RStomel Ah. Britishe nachas.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 06:06:57 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544925918933659648</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544925918933659648</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@trekonomics For some. I expect President DeSantis hopes to remove that nail.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 05:59:43 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544924100694614016</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544924100694614016</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@DandiaAsad @JPoetryProject Please! The cover picture was photoshopped and does not reflect an actual Coney Island venue.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 05:21:24 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544914457217974272</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544914457217974272</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@DandiaAsad Okay, the first book of poetry @JPoetryProject published features Coney Island on one of its cover. The author has passed on, but if I wanted to hold a Jewish poetry reading there, is there a potential venue I could reach out to?&#10;&#10;@DandiaAsad @JPoetryProject https://t.co/i2SLFi2Nek&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 05:00:33 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544909209493553155</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544909209493553155</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@EladNehorai Here’s the thing. If the violence reflects a background antisemitism but doesn’t explicitly make it an ideology, that *increases* the responsibility of those who foster the background noise of racism and antisemitism.&#10;&#10;@EladNehorai But if that’s the case, blame can’t be placed solely on the internet subculture, but on the wider post 2016 culture.&#10;&#10;@EladNehorai But — and it’s a big but — it’s unseemly and impossible for NPR to pin any blame on the Republican Party.&#10;&#10;@EladNehorai The subculture can focus on accelerationism because Tucker Carlson et al provide the basic principles.&#10;&#10;@EladNehorai As always, with great power comes great ability to get away with great crime.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 04:54:11 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544907610222170114</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544907610222170114</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@elivalley Hard to believe that a movement which has as a leading spokesman someone who said God demands that thoughtful non-Orthodox Jews be “hated like vermin” could fall so low.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 04:45:24 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544905399094185986</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544905399094185986</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@jh_swanson @RokhlK He’s just following in the footsteps of Mark Levin, Dennis Prager, Whatshisnane Horowitz, and Ben Shapiro. It’s a very good grift. And he will definitely outlive his fellow yidden who precede him to the ovens.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 04:17:44 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544898434162954241</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544898434162954241</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@DykeCrone @nytmike Doesn’t sound like it needs a section: Just a corrupt IRS chief and some lieutenants in the chain of command.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 04:09:10 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544896279133753345</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544896279133753345</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@jamesdnicoll @hammard_1987 If slide rules were good enough for Podkayne of Mars….&#10;&#10;@jamesdnicoll @hammard_1987 Though the first whoah! moment in my recent reread was the opening scene, in which the entire action is prompted by the teenager roaming the halls because the magazines in the waiting room were boring.&#10;&#10;@jamesdnicoll @hammard_1987 Give Podkayne an iPhone to text her friends or watch TikTok and the whole plot would have been aborted.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:59:02 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544893730540371971</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544893730540371971</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>If the Republicans hadn’t decided to oppose the assault weapon ban, this child would not be an orphan. https://t.co/uONLNrrPpK&#10;&#10;Maybe it’s time to question whether unapologetic Republican apparatchiks should have a place in polite Jewish society.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:51:48 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544891908643864582</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544891908643864582</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@LemieuxLGM Interesting. I definitely bought into this — I didn’t feel the 2000 election mattered much. Probably most of my news consumption at that point was still the NYTimes; I had let my old New Republic subscription lapse.&#10;&#10;@LemieuxLGM It took Paul Krugman and the liberal blogosphere to radicalize me. But as Krugman repeatedly noted, his distress over Bush was rooted in reading his publicly available plans.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:40:15 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544889001362038784</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544889001362038784</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@YehudisFletcher @Anzovina @cwjisrael @RStomel APPG?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544886500843814912</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544886500843814912</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@trekonomics Sorry, but Space Seed was just one episode. This is a lifestyle.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:28:55 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544886150506102784</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544886150506102784</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@sesmith @erinbiba Remember: According to American Jewish communal leadership, boycotting West Bank settlements is hair on fire antisemitism, but a political party and its aligned television network regularly scapegoating a Jewish billionaire for everything they hate about the other party is not.&#10;&#10;@sesmith @erinbiba Related: A handful of congressman voting against aid to Israel out of Palestinian sympathies is an emergency, even though it passes nonetheless, but hate crime legislation being opposed across the board by a political party is not to be noted.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 03:00:09 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544878912785846278</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544878912785846278</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@shane_burley1 @areidross Already pledged. But FYI — as someone who is about to launch a Kickstarter for a book so is thinking about these things — my preference would have been for a paperback plus ebook tier, since I collect books but seem to read more ebooks. Forced to choose, I pledged the ebook.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 02:52:24 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544876961926889473</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544876961926889473</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@azforeman If only there were an actual pill for that (outside the Oz books, where L Frank Baum imagined language pills in 1902)! My daughter tried taking Arabic in high school but couldn’t master the trickier consonants.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 02:34:51 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544872544695685120</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544872544695685120</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@JamesFallows Seriously though: I think it’s a real failure that FB doesn’t let my significant other share a view of her feed with me and vice versa. My parents were aware of the media each other consumed.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 02:26:31 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544870448831275008</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544870448831275008</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@datadivajf Probably my favorite episode of all.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 02:24:35 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544869958894718976</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544869958894718976</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@trekonomics Donkey Kong is not going to play itself.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 20:45:50 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544784713042329602</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544784713042329602</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@AkivaMCohen This is related to “everyone in a entitled to their own opinion; who an I to judge them” and “Someone has to play devils advocate so it might as well be me.”&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 20:44:46 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544784443654684674</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1544784443654684674</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
