<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- RSS generated by opmltweets v1.4.10 on Sun, 29 May 2022 02:27:40 GMT -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:source="http://source.scripting.com/">
	<channel>
		<title>yudel tweets</title>
		<link>http://twitter.com/yudel</link>
		<description>A feed of recent tweets from yudel.</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 02:20:48 GMT</pubDate>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<generator>opmltweets v1.4.10</generator>
		<docs>http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 02:27:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<cloud domain="rpc.rsscloud.io" port="5337" path="/pleaseNotify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
		<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
		<source:localTime>Sat, May 28, 2022 10:27 PM EDT</source:localTime>
		<item>
			<description>@DBashIdeas Which my one-time Zohar hevrusa @kavvanah of course read and passed on to me.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 02:20:48 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530735879840464896</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530735879840464896</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@DBashIdeas You'd have to look at the way &quot;The Zohar&quot; is in part the creation of the printer who first collected the Aramaic manuscripts, some of which had circulated separately.&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas And the way that printing enabled a book that proclaimed to be holy but was not already considered authoritative to circulate widely -- and thereby be accepted and become canon.&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas How much did the steadily declining price of print enable the spread of Chassidus in the 18th century?&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas Would the Baal Hatanya had written his own Shulchan Aruch, which spoke on behalf of a small portion of the Ashkenazic community, if printing costs were what they had been in the time of the Shulchan Aruch and the Rama, who between two of the wrote down the halacha for all Jewry?&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas Obviously, the Haskala was a product of print, like the Renaissance which inspired it.&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas In the 20th century, someone reinvested money made selling lead dreidels on the Lower East Side to buy a printing press and founded Ktav.&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas The development of computer-based phototypesetting meant that ArtScroll could start doing pre-Mac proto-desktop publishing for a relative pittance -- and once they bought that for invitations, why not write a commentary on Megilat Esther?&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas It shouldn't be too hard to find the costs of typesetting a volume of the Soncino Tanakh in the 40s versus an Artscroll volume in the 80s.&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas My @BenYehudaPress only exists because of cheaper printing technology. The spark was my discovery of the availability of Print on Demand technology coupled with widespread distribution.&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas @BenYehudaPress I don't need to sell 5,000 copies to justify printing costs, and I don't have to warehouse 5,000 copies until they all sell.&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas @BenYehudaPress Going back a generation, it's hard to believe that the ability of everyone in the YU beis medresh to have a $20 photo offset set of Shas didn't have any affect on what was learned and taught.&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas @BenYehudaPress Were there shiurim that dealt with a list of sources that would be unfeasible to demand of students in Volozhin? Certainly a topic for investigation.&#10;&#10;@DBashIdeas @BenYehudaPress The final chapter of the book describes Sefaria, its founding, its funding, and its acquisition of the Steinsaltz translation of Shas. I'm very much looking forward to the repercussions of that act in the decades ahead.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 02:03:30 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530731526945751040</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530731526945751040</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>&quot;This Old Man: Rough and Rowdy Days, Shadow Kingdom, and the 2022 Tour show Bob Dylan writing (and rewriting) for his elderly vocal range -- and perspective.&quot;&#10;Has anybody written this essay yet?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 01:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530729638821081088</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530729638821081088</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Your occasional reminder that AIPAC is helping elect the Republican congressmen who enabled this slaughter. https://t.co/k7NuLpBQqg&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 01:47:44 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530727560199512064</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530727560199512064</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@DandiaAsad “Or you could be honest and say, ‘A Republican named Newt Gingrich saw a wedge issue and ran with it.’”&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:22:33 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530706122138701824</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530706122138701824</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@c_o_bernstein Well, actually. https://t.co/v7N9NPp7x1&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:41 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530700619106877440</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530700619106877440</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@trekonomics So my NJ neighbor is currently at 27 on Amazon after less than a week. I once could translate that to sales but no longer can. Figures recalculate hourly so it’s selling steadily.&#10;&#10;@trekonomics It’s offering deeper knowledge to people who believe history is determined by personalities rather than systems and processes. Which is how Americans are generally taught to understand history.&#10;&#10;@trekonomics They are also taught to be dispassionate about history. I can’t imagine writing a “sexy” book about Trump that doesn’t rely on either black humor or moral outrage to make readers turn pages essentially about inter office memos.&#10;&#10;@trekonomics Here’s the “real” people behind the Dior basically uses porn to keep the pages turning.&#10;&#10;@trekonomics But the motive of the purchasers is a noble one.&#10;&#10;@trekonomics Disclaimer: I have so far succeeded in avoiding reading anything about the book and intend to continue so until final sales are revealed at the time of remaindering.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 23:28:02 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530692401353969664</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530692401353969664</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@swordsjew Sounds feline but ok.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 23:19:52 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530690347600338944</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530690347600338944</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@WatergateDayOf @SpiroAgnewGhost Shouldn’t there also be a Oval Office Day of account, tweeting out excerpts of that day’s transcripts?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 23:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530689123320795136</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530689123320795136</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@delong There are multiple versions so I don’t think anything can be pinned down. If you want me to tag the experts on the pre-recording manuscripts and the performed variations, I can summon them.&#10;&#10;@delong Definitive deep dive into the unpublished pocket notebooks, now on display in Tulsa: https://t.co/JHCaDDXpZK&#10;&#10;@delong Possible source of one of the lines? https://t.co/7rChZPQY3P&#10;&#10;@delong 1984 tour variations. https://t.co/pxeOsUE4ZS&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 23:04:14 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530686412227485696</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530686412227485696</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@prof_goldberg Case name itself sounds like a hate crime.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 22:21:06 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530675559641935872</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530675559641935872</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@froomkin The Sulzbergers are probably the most liberal people in their social circle. And the execs who buy ads are probably not liberal.&#10;&#10;@froomkin They can’t alienate the half of the age-and-wealth demographic that identify as Republican.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 21:52:44 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530668418512621568</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530668418512621568</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@ljordanplatt @froomkin I’m happy you’re telling them that!&#10;&#10;@ljordanplatt @froomkin But even more importantly, whatever the owner’s politics, they don’t want to anger threat Republicans in their own social circle, among their advertisers, and their subscribers.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 21:49:32 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530667613575335937</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530667613575335937</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@trekonomics For some people it’s always 1945.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 21:48:36 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530667378933104640</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530667378933104640</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Some theology in memory of former NCSY and OU leader Rabbi Pinchas Stolper https://t.co/LMadGRY6ff&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 21:17:20 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530659511853322240</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530659511853322240</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@HeerJeet Military “respect the gun” discipline is real an effective. I got a bit second hand from my dad. It won’t stop the killer with a rifle, perhaps, but would prevent all the kids killed in handgun “accidents.”&#10;&#10;@HeerJeet I suspect that most military veterans with kids are horrified by this picture. https://t.co/c9soB9lXtf&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 20:59:32 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530655032806461441</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530655032806461441</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@DandiaAsad 2 million people. Is there a single daily paper?&#10;&#10;@DandiaAsad Time to buy the rights for the Daily Eagle from the heirs of Meir Kahane.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 20:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530652129291128832</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530652129291128832</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@GershomG Lots of “accidental” gun tragedies here that wouldn’t happen if the gun owners had first been indoctrinated into military discipline of proper gun respect.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 17:49:41 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530607255397224451</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530607255397224451</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@GershomG @yasmingorenberg 70s-style color grading! You raised her well!&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 17:47:33 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530606716508852227</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530606716508852227</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@jeremysarna @babyboymonaghan We’re probably due for a “Bertha” revival on the naming front. Along with “Edna.”&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 16:41:36 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530590119517904896</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530590119517904896</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@pzmyers Trans pronoun menace? Dawkins is now opposed to memetic evolution?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 12:39:54 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530529296237973504</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530529296237973504</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@trekonomics @Frances_Coppola They know because they know how easy it is to do accidentally.&#10;&#10;@trekonomics @Frances_Coppola I am very grateful my on the job mistakes hurt no one and cost nothing.&#10;&#10;@trekonomics @Frances_Coppola But despite all this, America still had some delightful murderers. https://t.co/LKELJnJOd3&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 09:40:02 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530484030994583554</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530484030994583554</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@hardmaru Google already can’t handle GPT generated text. In fact, it seems to be effectively polluting the web by feeding search terms to sites that then generate GPT gibberish that has great SEO, and which profit by selling Google ads.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 06:52:16 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530441808643227648</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530441808643227648</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@SapioSiren @swordsjew It warms my boomer heart to see young folk who still know Perl (not that I ever mastered it at this level).&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 05:20:42 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530418765195661312</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530418765195661312</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@hardmaru So I play a lot with the text generator at https://t.co/OdngmloMv0 and it’s a very strange thing. Fictional stories that read like news articles and reflect an enormous range of knowledge only partially remembered. The AI is very knowledgeable but only somewhat smart. Or drunk.&#10;&#10;@hardmaru But I hesitate to post the results online because it has real people saying things in their fields of expertise that are of course not true.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 05:10:16 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530416139263741952</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530416139263741952</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
