<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- RSS generated by opmltweets v1.4.10 on Fri, 27 May 2022 02:48:35 GMT -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:source="http://source.scripting.com/">
	<channel>
		<title>yudel tweets</title>
		<link>http://twitter.com/yudel</link>
		<description>A feed of recent tweets from yudel.</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 02:48:03 GMT</pubDate>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<generator>opmltweets v1.4.10</generator>
		<docs>http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 02:48:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<cloud domain="rpc.rsscloud.io" port="5337" path="/pleaseNotify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
		<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
		<source:localTime>Thu, May 26, 2022 10:48 PM EDT</source:localTime>
		<item>
			<description>Hard to believe we’ve been on Twitter for years without spotting a Yehezkel Kaufman reference but glad to say that drought is over. https://t.co/HebvHK09jN&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 02:48:03 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530017963860008960</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1530017963860008960</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>This may well be deeply concerning. But…. https://t.co/YjDYJyogqX&#10;&#10;One distressing fact in the present moment is that American governance is deeply broken by the Republican prioritization of waging war against the Democrats above everything else.&#10;&#10;The Atlantic recently reported that when Syria crossed Obama’s red line and used poison gas, Obama decided that waging was was a job for Congress and he approached McConnell — who declined to act.&#10;&#10;After all, why hand Obama a foreign policy win?&#10;&#10;As we’ve seen with the slow walking of approving key foreign policy posts, the Republicans are doing the minimum to support US foreign policy.&#10;&#10;(Note that they allowed a Republican to hold up Iron Dome aid, figuring that Israel supporters wouldn’t hold the party accountable, and they were right. As @rmneiss has documented, AIPAC spent ten times more attacking the Democrats who initially opposed the aid than&#10;&#10;the Republican who continued to object for several more months.)&#10;&#10;From the perspective of Joe Biden, foreign policy as usual saves him from Republican criticism. And they, for better or worse, seems to be a major goal of his.&#10;&#10;If the Iran deal falls apart, that will be why. Unlike Obama, who was an idealist, Biden will be making a political decision. I think Obama was legit scared by Bibi into seeking the deal — much to Bibi’s chagrin, of course.&#10;&#10;Faced with the mental image of nuked Israelis, Obama was willing to spend political capital to slow Iran’s drive to the bomb. Biden is not.&#10;&#10;Frankly, I can’t say I blame him.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:59:04 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529990537268416517</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529990537268416517</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@allshiny Hmmm. A possible recommendation for us guilty carnivores. (Or non-practicing vegetarians, as we prefer to call ourselves.) if I may ask: How old were you when you stopped eating meat?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:53:51 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529989223473881088</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529989223473881088</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@sirosenbaum See, they give away for free, and even professionals wonder why they can’t make $1/word like in olden times.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529982238158475274</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529982238158475274</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@ShulimLeifer Whereas his school would no doubt suggest Tehillim. Which I believe were tried during last century’s great German unpleasantness. How did that work out again?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529980874061762560</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529980874061762560</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@AD_Lobel I would not travel with that man, who clearly does not know how to hire qualified people. Though really, preferring to communicate by snailmail is a red flag, as I tell people who don’t want to submit doc or pdf files.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:18:32 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529980336628813825</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529980336628813825</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@evawyner @kampeas Lot of people loved President Obama, but so few renamed their school after him…. :-)&#10;&#10;@evawyner @kampeas I went to Cleveland’s Agnon School, which was also renamed, so I share in the alumni outrage over the renaming.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:12:03 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529978704251834383</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529978704251834383</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@johnastoehr Can’t believe I missed this piece about him in November. https://t.co/bcT6VZflbj&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 23:27:28 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529967484694061063</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529967484694061063</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@evawyner @kampeas Wasn’t it still Akiva in his day?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 23:13:17 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529963916939476992</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529963916939476992</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@ParkerMolloy I will say that I once saw him and his wife autograph books at a local supermarket, which has to be as close to hell a man like him can get this side of a prison or hospital.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 22:52:02 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529958566056103936</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529958566056103936</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@YehudahMirsky Really negligent of Solomon not to get a permanent copyright on it, as I believe was done by the British parliament for Peter Pan.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 22:48:59 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529957800738267139</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529957800738267139</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@hondanhon Any failure to hire a bunch of Cubans to kidnap six Republican senators and threaten to shoot them one by one until the Court is expanded and the filibuster is repealed is a Democratic failure.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 19:55:52 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529914234192154655</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529914234192154655</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>It’s possible that @MarginaliaROB is only the second publication to write about this theological work. If you’re not following them, you should. https://t.co/zIQlzVzo9i&#10;&#10;The first might have been the @JewishStandard. But since not all Jewish thought is written by North Jersey authors, Marginalia is a more comprehensive resource.&#10;&#10;Here’s my piece: https://t.co/hb38Jg5Rii&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 17:01:36 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529870378520268802</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529870378520268802</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>If one door was good enough for Noah’s ark…. https://t.co/9pzuCDCRlY&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 16:57:30 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529869348076195840</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529869348076195840</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@sillyhead I mean, we’re close to the point where voting for a Democrat will be proof of antisemitism, so….&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 16:53:46 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529868407151140867</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529868407151140867</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@datadivajf It’s the future! And didn’t we see intelligent plasma last week!&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 15:31:29 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529847698983211008</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529847698983211008</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@Octalthorpe @datadivajf Seems likely that they’re setting up for the prediction to fail. One of the kids he sees himself saving — whose records he called up in Ep 3 — is going to die. I wonder if the writers will give them a red shirt.&#10;&#10;@Octalthorpe @datadivajf I wonder if that will be part of a season cliffhanger.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 15:21:46 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529845255822090245</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529845255822090245</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@datadivajf @Octalthorpe What they pulled off in Return to Tomorrow wasn't really much more plausible. (I rewatched it recently in preparation for Picard, but it also relevant to the question of beaming up people and sedating them in sickbay before they cause problems.)&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 15:08:33 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529841926849044489</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529841926849044489</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@typolad Have to admit that drinking is better than smoking for teddy bears. But combining the two is insanely hazardous.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 13:23:13 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529815421225947136</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529815421225947136</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@Octalthorpe @datadivajf Would Jim Kirk had made all those insanely risky decisions if he hadn’t been mentored by Pike (possibly) and his crew?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 13:21:31 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529814992765300736</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529814992765300736</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>This. Very much this. https://t.co/qkZzK0zCu1&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 12:46:27 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529806167962173441</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529806167962173441</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@Chronotope Misses a key point: taking out two Republicans would mean that Manchin doesn’t matter.&#10;&#10;@Chronotope And if you get a reasonable popular pair hostage, you might find a couple others wiling to repeal the fillibuster to avoid a possibly messy hostage rescue.&#10;&#10;@Chronotope Really, seize four Republican senators and threaten to start shooting one by one until the Senate 1) Expands the Supreme Court and 2) Modified the Filibuster.&#10;&#10;@Chronotope Executing such a plot is beyond my resources -- for better or for worse -- but I challenge anyone to show how it would not be acceptable according to Jewish law, as laid out by Rabbi Moshe Tendler in his 1984 defending the Jewish terrorist underground.&#10;&#10;@Chronotope Ah, those days when publishing a journal evenly divided between pro- and anti- terror supporters got you (correctly) branded as a liberal in the college cafeteria, because the default Orthodox position was pro-terror.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 12:28:18 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529801599429881857</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529801599429881857</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>To quote a friend: The “big tent” bipartisan approach that once gave organizations like the Federation their power is now weakening and destroying them from the inside. https://t.co/zOY5Iikgso&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 12:04:59 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529795733267828740</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529795733267828740</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>To amplify: Stolper ran the youth group for the Orthodox Union. That's the umbrella group for most modern Orthodox shuls. And the OU symbol you see on many kosher products. https://t.co/XztInABECl&#10;&#10;Stolper, as the quoted thread notes, ignored victims of his employee Rabbi Baruch Lanner. Why? In part, because, as is alleged to have told the victims, because the employees were doing so much good in spreading &quot;Torah.&quot;&#10;&#10;And in part, because as a good Orthodox Jew he had been trained to regard the word of a rabbi above that of a girl.&#10;&#10;As an Orthodox Jew, he also -- whether consciously or unconsciously -- believed in the Talmudic dictum that God protects those who are doing a mitzvah.&#10;&#10;It was a dictum quoted by Israeli government minister Aryeh Deri last year, dismissing the pleas of officials to impose safety measures on the Lag Ba'omer celebrations in Meron. The measures weren't imposed. 45 people died. Including a kid who lived one town over from mine.&#10;&#10;My daughter was at the pilgrimage. She saw the stretchers pass by with the victims.&#10;&#10;My daughter is named for a victim of Pinchas Stolper's NCSY.&#10;&#10;In 1981, we were at a Shabbaton in Utica, New York. The ground was covered with snow. We were walking back from shul on a Friday night. At one spot, the sidewalk wasn't shoveled. Most of the kids walking home started walking in the street.&#10;&#10;Safety, of course, dictates that you don't walk in the street in the direction of traffic. So I continued walking, slowly, on top of the huge piles of snow.&#10;&#10;Safety, of course, would dictate that the advisors -- college students -- would have the group cross over the street to the other side. But safety was not a top concern for NCSY.&#10;&#10;If safety had been a top concern at NCSY, the director of New Jersey's Junior NCSY chapter would not now stand accused of having sent a girl home in Baruch Lanner's car, where she was allegedly raped.&#10;&#10;That junior NCSY director is now a shul rabbi here in Teaneck, because Torah &quot;knowledge&quot; always trumps demonstrable bad judgement in the Orthodox world of the OU.&#10;&#10;Meanwhile, downtown, a political bigwig had spent the evening drinking. He drove through the group walking home. He killed three girls.&#10;&#10;One was my sister.&#10;&#10;At the time, I was an NCSY true believer. My family didn't sue.&#10;&#10;At the time, as an Orthodox true believer, I looked immediately to my sins. What had I done to deserve this? That is, after all, one of the theologies expressed in traditional Judaism.&#10;&#10;I have come to understand that what I did to deserve it -- what my sister did to deserve it -- was to assume that Orthodox Judaism could provide a safe environment. When, at its theological core, it can't.&#10;&#10;Now, had my sister decided instead to spend the weekend with her Camp Ramah friends -- well, Camp Ramah has its problems too, as we've seen this month. But it knows better than to preach fairy tales about a God who saves its worshippers.&#10;&#10;At its core, contemporary Orthodox Judaism is a form of Holocaust denial.&#10;&#10;See Telushkin's letter, critiquing someone I am proud to have published, arguing in effect that the Holocaust doesn't keep him up at night because, thanks to God's posthumous justice, it's all good. https://t.co/iSvKYCgDk4&#10;&#10;The rot lies very, very deep in the OU and its rabbinic leadership.&#10;&#10;An excerpt from the current NCSY lawsuit, at a point when Jane Doe #3 is on an NCSY Israel trip, where Lanner is abusing her. She tells Stolper about it.&#10;&#10;From the lawsuit: &quot;Rabbi Stolper responded, “...but are you having a good time?”&#10;&#10;He took no action and summarily dismissed Jane Doe #3 repeatedly saying, 'He [Lanner] does so much&#10;good; it’s important what he’s doing.'&quot;&#10;&#10;The good, of course, is spreading the true religion of Orthodox Judaism. In its OU form, that religion teaches that the study of the Talmud provides access to the mind of God, and touches on a supernal wisdom.&#10;&#10;Relatedly, traditional Jewish observance will bring one to a greater sense of ethics.&#10;&#10;Both of those theories have been robustly disproved, as @Shmarya documented over the course of a decade or so at Failed Messiah.&#10;&#10;The matter of Baruch Lanner and NCSY provides a very clear example of this.&#10;&#10;Briefly: A &quot;court&quot; made up of Yeshiva University's leading Talmudists was established to judge the case of Baruch Lanner.&#10;&#10;Briefly: They botched it in every which way.&#10;&#10;Subsequently, one of the rabbis apologized. He did not admit, however, that his ability to err so grievously undermined all of the theological claims of the value of Talmud study.&#10;&#10;He had devoted his life to the study and teaching of Jewish law, he had encouraged others to do the same, and when it actually came time to apply it, to make a difference in someone's life -- he fucked it up.&#10;&#10;Really, the world would have been better off had spent the decades developing video games.&#10;&#10;Needless to say, that one failing -- which hurt multiple people, including the girls Lanner went on to abuse -- is totally forgiven by the good Orthodox Jews of Bergen County, where Rabbi Willig is a frequent and welcome speaker.&#10;&#10;Yesterday, after my attacks on AIPAC for funding the Republicans who put AR-15s in the hands of teens, I was admonished by my employer that I should tone down my tweeting.&#10;&#10;For the record, my views are mine alone, not those of my paper.&#10;&#10;OU and NCSY are major advertisers at my paper. I have generally kept silent about it.&#10;&#10;The death of Pinchas Stolper reminds me that my articles about NCSY and OU activities -- in which none of my animus intrudes -- may lead people to take part in those events.&#10;&#10;Perhaps some kids enrolls in a Jewish school because the OU is able to lower the tuition thanks to the advocacy efforts I am scheduled to write about later today.&#10;&#10;Perhaps one of those kids is then abused or killed as a result of the otherworldly Orthodox theology.&#10;&#10;I'm sorry. I just can't any more.&#10;&#10;But back to Stolper: Obviously, I don't hope he rots in hell. Because there is no such place.&#10;&#10;And the reason I know there is no such place is -- despite what Egyptian mythology might have you believe, as would its Jewish offshoots -- a life can't be measured on a one-dimensional scale of good or bad.&#10;&#10;I mean, Stinky Pinky no doubt did good too.&#10;&#10;And much of what Stinky Pinky did that was evil he sincerely believed was good.&#10;&#10;There is no meaningful guidance of how to live one's life given at Sinai. We are on our own here.&#10;&#10;It's not always a pleasant thing to know -- I remember my disappointment at an NCSY Shabbaton a year after my sister's death when I read the Talmud's &quot;proofs&quot; of the resurrection of the dead.&#10;&#10;Spoiler: That doctrine isn't in the Torah, and the rabbis knew it.&#10;&#10;Might as well get your faith from Bruce Springsteen. https://t.co/jrCrsWrKD6&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 11:07:13 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529781194325381121</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529781194325381121</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@richterscale You missed a step: Quote the Bible to anoint your weapons with the oil of Holy War.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 20:23:36 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529558826432741376</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529558826432741376</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
