<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- RSS generated by opmltweets v1.4.10 on Thu, 26 May 2022 12:07:57 GMT -->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:source="http://source.scripting.com/">
	<channel>
		<title>yudel tweets</title>
		<link>http://twitter.com/yudel</link>
		<description>A feed of recent tweets from yudel.</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 12:04:59 GMT</pubDate>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<generator>opmltweets v1.4.10</generator>
		<docs>http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 12:07:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<cloud domain="rpc.rsscloud.io" port="5337" path="/pleaseNotify" registerProcedure="" protocol="http-post" />
		<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
		<source:localTime>Thu, May 26, 2022 8:07 AM EDT</source:localTime>
		<item>
			<description>To quote a friend: The “big tent” bipartisan approach that once gave organizations like the Federation their power is now weakening and destroying them from the inside. https://t.co/zOY5Iikgso&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 12:04:59 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529795733267828740</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529795733267828740</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>To amplify: Stolper ran the youth group for the Orthodox Union. That's the umbrella group for most modern Orthodox shuls. And the OU symbol you see on many kosher products. https://t.co/XztInABECl&#10;&#10;Stolper, as the quoted thread notes, ignored victims of his employee Rabbi Baruch Lanner. Why? In part, because, as is alleged to have told the victims, because the employees were doing so much good in spreading &quot;Torah.&quot;&#10;&#10;And in part, because as a good Orthodox Jew he had been trained to regard the word of a rabbi above that of a girl.&#10;&#10;As an Orthodox Jew, he also -- whether consciously or unconsciously -- believed in the Talmudic dictum that God protects those who are doing a mitzvah.&#10;&#10;It was a dictum quoted by Israeli government minister Aryeh Deri last year, dismissing the pleas of officials to impose safety measures on the Lag Ba'omer celebrations in Meron. The measures weren't imposed. 45 people died. Including a kid who lived one town over from mine.&#10;&#10;My daughter was at the pilgrimage. She saw the stretchers pass by with the victims.&#10;&#10;My daughter is named for a victim of Pinchas Stolper's NCSY.&#10;&#10;In 1981, we were at a Shabbaton in Utica, New York. The ground was covered with snow. We were walking back from shul on a Friday night. At one spot, the sidewalk wasn't shoveled. Most of the kids walking home started walking in the street.&#10;&#10;Safety, of course, dictates that you don't walk in the street in the direction of traffic. So I continued walking, slowly, on top of the huge piles of snow.&#10;&#10;Safety, of course, would dictate that the advisors -- college students -- would have the group cross over the street to the other side. But safety was not a top concern for NCSY.&#10;&#10;If safety had been a top concern at NCSY, the director of New Jersey's Junior NCSY chapter would not now stand accused of having sent a girl home in Baruch Lanner's car, where she was allegedly raped.&#10;&#10;That junior NCSY director is now a shul rabbi here in Teaneck, because Torah &quot;knowledge&quot; always trumps demonstrable bad judgement in the Orthodox world of the OU.&#10;&#10;Meanwhile, downtown, a political bigwig had spent the evening drinking. He drove through the group walking home. He killed three girls.&#10;&#10;One was my sister.&#10;&#10;At the time, I was an NCSY true believer. My family didn't sue.&#10;&#10;At the time, as an Orthodox true believer, I looked immediately to my sins. What had I done to deserve this? That is, after all, one of the theologies expressed in traditional Judaism.&#10;&#10;I have come to understand that what I did to deserve it -- what my sister did to deserve it -- was to assume that Orthodox Judaism could provide a safe environment. When, at its theological core, it can't.&#10;&#10;Now, had my sister decided instead to spend the weekend with her Camp Ramah friends -- well, Camp Ramah has its problems too, as we've seen this month. But it knows better than to preach fairy tales about a God who saves its worshippers.&#10;&#10;At its core, contemporary Orthodox Judaism is a form of Holocaust denial.&#10;&#10;See Telushkin's letter, critiquing someone I am proud to have published, arguing in effect that the Holocaust doesn't keep him up at night because, thanks to God's posthumous justice, it's all good. https://t.co/iSvKYCgDk4&#10;&#10;The rot lies very, very deep in the OU and its rabbinic leadership.&#10;&#10;An excerpt from the current NCSY lawsuit, at a point when Jane Doe #3 is on an NCSY Israel trip, where Lanner is abusing her. She tells Stolper about it.&#10;&#10;From the lawsuit: &quot;Rabbi Stolper responded, “...but are you having a good time?”&#10;&#10;He took no action and summarily dismissed Jane Doe #3 repeatedly saying, 'He [Lanner] does so much&#10;good; it’s important what he’s doing.'&quot;&#10;&#10;The good, of course, is spreading the true religion of Orthodox Judaism. In its OU form, that religion teaches that the study of the Talmud provides access to the mind of God, and touches on a supernal wisdom.&#10;&#10;Relatedly, traditional Jewish observance will bring one to a greater sense of ethics.&#10;&#10;Both of those theories have been robustly disproved, as @Shmarya documented over the course of a decade or so at Failed Messiah.&#10;&#10;The matter of Baruch Lanner and NCSY provides a very clear example of this.&#10;&#10;Briefly: A &quot;court&quot; made up of Yeshiva University's leading Talmudists was established to judge the case of Baruch Lanner.&#10;&#10;Briefly: They botched it in every which way.&#10;&#10;Subsequently, one of the rabbis apologized. He did not admit, however, that his ability to err so grievously undermined all of the theological claims of the value of Talmud study.&#10;&#10;He had devoted his life to the study and teaching of Jewish law, he had encouraged others to do the same, and when it actually came time to apply it, to make a difference in someone's life -- he fucked it up.&#10;&#10;Really, the world would have been better off had spent the decades developing video games.&#10;&#10;Needless to say, that one failing -- which hurt multiple people, including the girls Lanner went on to abuse -- is totally forgiven by the good Orthodox Jews of Bergen County, where Rabbi Willig is a frequent and welcome speaker.&#10;&#10;Yesterday, after my attacks on AIPAC for funding the Republicans who put AR-15s in the hands of teens, I was admonished by my employer that I should tone down my tweeting.&#10;&#10;For the record, my views are mine alone, not those of my paper.&#10;&#10;OU and NCSY are major advertisers at my paper. I have generally kept silent about it.&#10;&#10;The death of Pinchas Stolper reminds me that my articles about NCSY and OU activities -- in which none of my animus intrudes -- may lead people to take part in those events.&#10;&#10;Perhaps some kids enrolls in a Jewish school because the OU is able to lower the tuition thanks to the advocacy efforts I am scheduled to write about later today.&#10;&#10;Perhaps one of those kids is then abused or killed as a result of the otherworldly Orthodox theology.&#10;&#10;I'm sorry. I just can't any more.&#10;&#10;But back to Stolper: Obviously, I don't hope he rots in hell. Because there is no such place.&#10;&#10;And the reason I know there is no such place is -- despite what Egyptian mythology might have you believe, as would its Jewish offshoots -- a life can't be measured on a one-dimensional scale of good or bad.&#10;&#10;I mean, Stinky Pinky no doubt did good too.&#10;&#10;And much of what Stinky Pinky did that was evil he sincerely believed was good.&#10;&#10;There is no meaningful guidance of how to live one's life given at Sinai. We are on our own here.&#10;&#10;It's not always a pleasant thing to know -- I remember my disappointment at an NCSY Shabbaton a year after my sister's death when I read the Talmud's &quot;proofs&quot; of the resurrection of the dead.&#10;&#10;Spoiler: That doctrine isn't in the Torah, and the rabbis knew it.&#10;&#10;Might as well get your faith from Bruce Springsteen. https://t.co/jrCrsWrKD6&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 11:07:13 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529781194325381121</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529781194325381121</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@richterscale You missed a step: Quote the Bible to anoint your weapons with the oil of Holy War.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 20:23:36 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529558826432741376</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529558826432741376</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@tara_chara But there will be, following the Second American Revolution. https://t.co/F1sC6HyiUd&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 20:21:53 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529558391592562690</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529558391592562690</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@EladNehorai Look, it’s not good for the Jews to be too pro-journalist. Don’t want to offend President DeSantis.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 19:45:19 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529549189306269696</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529549189306269696</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@EladNehorai @AJCGlobal @CNN Pretty antizionist if you to imply there’s a distinction.&#10;&#10;@EladNehorai @AJCGlobal @CNN Pretty antisemitic if you to be antizionist.&#10;&#10;@EladNehorai @AJCGlobal @CNN Pretty antiTorah of you to oppose the killing of a journalist, whose whole profession is a violation of lashon hora.&#10;&#10;@EladNehorai @AJCGlobal @CNN Pretty anti-Israel of you to oppose the killing of a journalist at a time when Israel’s foreign policy needs require drawing close to a government that murders journalists.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 19:39:13 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529547654123999234</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529547654123999234</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@kampeas Counterpoint: proposing policy reflects a lack of faith in God, who ensures that all get their due in the works to come so 🤷‍♂️. Cf Telushkin here: https://t.co/iSvKYCgDk4&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 19:17:06 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529542089431736327</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529542089431736327</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@Shmarya The point of the guns is to commit genocide. First against the natives, then against  Ty slaves. And soon against the (((globalists))).&#10;&#10;@Shmarya I expect my final pleasures as I slave away in a Prager U Reeducation camp will be the occasional public executions of people like Nancy Pelosi and her fellow Hindenburg Democrats.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 17:48:21 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529519753924161539</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529519753924161539</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@trekonomics The fundamental principal is genocide and slavery. Remember that America was “discovered” by a man considered too cruel by monarchs who had just expelled hundreds of thousands of Jews.&#10;&#10;@trekonomics This is what conservatives stand for and why they can’t allow their idols to be toppled or their history to be honestly taught.&#10;&#10;@trekonomics https://t.co/3E0ShfDmtV&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 17:45:09 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529518951759335425</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529518951759335425</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@Atrios Too bad that SCOTUS will abolish the EPA before he could be charged for air pollution.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 17:43:09 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529518446043619329</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529518446043619329</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@DrZackaryBerger What if we assumed that the preferred policy of this Christian nation is that people meet Jesus as soon as possible, and put the burden of proof on people to reject that theology? I’m tired of imputing good intentions to people who consistently deliver bad results.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 17:40:39 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529517819523649538</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529517819523649538</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@ashleyfeinberg @DrZackaryBerger They won’t take action when Anerican school children are murdered, and both parties clarion to like school children.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 17:38:25 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529517255251435522</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529517255251435522</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@trekonomics It’s a slaver republic, not a democracy. The more slaves you brought with you to the colony of New Jersey, the more land you were granted.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 17:11:31 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529510486521290753</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529510486521290753</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@mjs_DC Time for a National Museum of Victims of Libertarianism on the Mall.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 17:08:07 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529509628610060289</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529509628610060289</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@micahinATL I’d like to think that his demands for “us” to do something is a call for stochastic terrorism.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 17:06:33 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529509237205901312</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529509237205901312</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@AndrewGhalili @dylanotes @jinsadc Ah. If you can’t trust a guy who lied to Congress, who can you trust?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 15:29:49 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529484892899360769</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529484892899360769</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Sad you’re not willing to trust Bibi Netanyahu’s strategic wisdom in this. https://t.co/KyIMvCYWuE&#10;&#10;Given his track record. https://t.co/dnJRosFUIA&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 15:28:31 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529484564623769601</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529484564623769601</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@ShulimLeifer What business would you recommend for making friends?&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 14:42:58 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529473103113355264</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529473103113355264</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@lrozen Sort of the flip side of Bibi so scaring Obama about the threat that he reached for the deal.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 14:34:04 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529470862058979329</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529470862058979329</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>This. https://t.co/x1JIxbPV3i&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 14:32:14 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529470401293819906</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529470401293819906</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>And yet, misogynist religions still get tax breaks. Maybe that should change. https://t.co/erumMdQiQc&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 14:11:43 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529465237405065216</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529465237405065216</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@joshtpm When you believe in heaven, you don’t need to deal with policy; you can count on God to give Anne Frank and Adolph Eichmann their aporopriate just desserts. https://t.co/iSvKYCgDk4&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 14:10:51 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529465019234144257</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529465019234144257</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@TheRaDR Did you see this post from earlier this month from the manufacturer of the murder weapon? https://t.co/uucbZe9oAw&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 14:06:25 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529463903746400257</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529463903746400257</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>Two words. Backpack nukes. https://t.co/xmJ8nvkMAR&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 13:56:13 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529461337373417472</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529461337373417472</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		<item>
			<description>@Will_Bunch @froomkin Two words: Hindenburg Democrats. More scared of their shadows then of the fascists they’re preparing to hand the keys to.&#10;&#10;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 13:52:10 GMT</pubDate>
			<link>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529460318161842177</link>
			<guid>https://twitter.com/yudel/status/1529460318161842177</guid>
			<source:account service="twitter">yudel</source:account>
			</item>
		</channel>
	</rss>
